Portfolio: https://bthalpin.com | https://github.com/bthalpin | https://github.com/bthalpin

I am a full stack software developer specializing in MERN stack. Since the moment I was exposed to programming, it was all I ever wanted to do. I have always had a passion for problem solving, but thought my love of logic puzzles would be something I would only ever do as a hobby. Software development has given me an avenue to not only do what I love, but also to engage me and challenge me to always improve my skills.

SKILLS

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, ReactJS, Bootstrap, Bulma

Backend: MySQL, Postgres, Express, Node, Django

Non-technical:

CREDENTIALS -

Rutgers Coding Bootcamp – May 2022

CompTIA A+ Certification - December 2017

B.S. - Mechanical Engineering - Rutgers University, School of Engineering (New Brunswick, NJ) - May 2003

RELATED EXPERIENCE

WHAT MOVIE WAS THAT?

https://bthalpin.github.io/What-Movie-Was-That | https://github.com/bthalpin/What-Movie-Was-That

JavaScript Developer

- Allows the user to look up any movie and get the movie information and a trailer to watch.
- This app fetches OMDB API to receive movie information and YouTube API to get a movie trailer. I was primarily focused on JavaScript, making the fetch requests, and using logic to manipulate the data to provide the user with the appropriate information
 - Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, Bulma JavaScript, OMDB API, and YouTube API

CODE OUIZ

https://github.com/bthalpin/Code-Quiz | https://bthalpin.github.io/Code-Quiz/

JavaScript Developer

- A quiz app that randomly selects a trivia question for the user.
- As sole software developer for the project I organized the code in a modular code structure so that it can be easily expanded on to make a more robust quiz app with user generated questions.
 - Tools/Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

WEATHER FORECAST

https://github.com/bthalpin/Weather-Forecast | https://bthalpin.github.io/Weather-Forecast/

JavaScript Developer

- A weather app that uses Open Weather API to display accurate weather information for up to five days, anywhere in the world.
- I developed a weather forecast ap
 - Tools/Languages: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, and Open Weather API

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

MORRIS-UNION JOINTURE COMMISSION – WARREN, NJ	2006 - 2022
Teacher's Assistant	
G-STAR INC. LOGISTICS DEPARTMENT – SOMERSET, NJ Assistant Manager of the distribution center in the U.S.	2005 – 2006
HOME DEPOT – BRIDGEWATER, NJ Head Cashier	2001 - 2005